在我们很小的时候，我们都开始混合颜色，我们学会了如何结合
We all started mixing colors when we were very young, and we learned how to combine
不同颜色的油漆，以产生我们想要的颜色。
different colors of paint to produce colors that we wanted.
对于光明，规则有点不同。
For light the rules are a little bit different.
如果我发出红光和蓝光，那两盏灯相交的地方我会去
If I shine a red light and a blue light, where those two lights intersect I’m going to
有一种紫色。
have a sort of purply color.
红灯与绿灯相交的地方，红灯和绿灯混合在一起，我是
Where the red light intersects a green light, where the red and green lights mix, I’m
将形成黄色。
going to form the color yellow.
绿光和蓝光重叠的地方，我将形成一种颜色
And where the green light and the blue light overlap I’m going to form a color we might
打电话给aqua。
call aqua.
所有三种颜色重叠的地方都有白色。
Where all three colors overlap we have white.
如果我们将这些红色，绿色和蓝色灯光视为我们的主要光源，那么通过混合
If we consider these red, green and blue lights as our primary light sources then by mixing
它们以不同的组合形成不同的颜色。
them in different combinations we can form different colors.
在这里，我们只看了几个简单的组合。
Here we’ve looked at just a few simple combinations.
让我们来看看我们的红色，绿色和蓝色原色的一些更复杂的组合。
Let’s look at some more sophisticated combinations of our red, green and blue primary colors.
此表显示了我们如何从特定数量的文件中创建多个命名颜色
This table shows how we can create a number of named colors from certain amounts of the
红色，绿色和蓝色的原色。
red, green and blue primaries.
这里表示的数字是我们的无符号8位整数
The numbers that are represented here are our unsigned 8-bit integer numbers that we’ve
之前遇到过，所以它们的范围在0到255之间。
encountered previously, so they range between 0 and 255.
因此，例如，如果我们想要创建一种名为镉红深的颜色，我们需要
So, for instance, if we wanted to create the color called cadmium red deep, we’d need
红色227。
a red amount of 227.
因为最大值是255，所以这是相当多的红色;绿色只有23个
So that’s a fair amount of red, given that the maximum value is 255; only 23 of green
和蓝色的13。
and 13 of blue.
所以这是一种主要由红色构成的颜色。
So this is a color that’s made up dominantly of red.
让我们来看看这里可能更平衡的另一种颜色......让我们来吧
Let’s have a look at another color here that’s perhaps a bit more balanced … let’s
看看粉红色。
look at hot pink.
它包含最大可能的红色，以及相当数量的绿色和公平
It contains the maximum possible amount of red, and a fair amount of green and a fair
蓝色的量。
amount of blue.
所以这是一个调色板。
So this is a palette.
我们可以混合来自任意数量的红色，绿色和蓝色的任意颜色，并且经常
We can mix an arbitrary color from an arbitrary amount of red, green and blue, and frequently
我们想给那个颜色一个人性化的名字。
we’d like to give that color a human friendly name.
我们可以使用工具箱函数colorname演示颜色名称查找。
We can demonstrate color name lookup using the toolbox function colorname.
让我们查看颜色栗色的定义，在这里我们看到红色的数量，
Let’s look up the definition of the color maroon, and here we see the amount of red,
绿色和蓝色需要创建颜色栗色。
green and blue required to create the color maroon.
这里的这些数字就是我们所说的标准化三刺激值。
These numbers here are what we call normalised tri-stimulus values.
也就是说，它们介于0和1之间。
That is, they lie between 0 and 1.
所以在这种情况下，红色通道中的0.4表示红色为40％，绿色只有2％，
So in this case, 0.4 in the red channel means there’s 40% red, there’s only 2 % green,
也许28％是蓝色的。
and perhaps 28 % blue.
该功能也可以执行反函数。
This function can perform the inverse function as well.
例如，如果我的颜色为0.1的红色，0.2的绿色和0.3的蓝色，那就是
For instance, if I had a color that had 0.1 of red, 0.2 of green and 0.3 of blue, it’s
颜色相当深，略带蓝色。
a fairly dark color and a bit bluish.
它正在抬头，它告诉我这是一种叫午夜蓝的颜色。
It’s looking up and it’s telling me it’s the color called midnight blue.
此函数有一个包含八到九百种不同颜色的数据库文件。
This function has got a database file that contains eight to nine hundred different colors.
我们也可以使用这种机制来创建彩色图像，为此我们需要拉动
We could also use this mechanism to create a color image, and to do that we need to pull
一点点技巧。
a little bit of a trick.
所以我要创建一个像素图像。
So I’m going to create a single pixel image.
使用MATLAB函数。
Use the MATLAB function ones.
我要创建一个包含一行一列和三个平面的图像。
I’m going to create an image with one row and one column, and three planes.
它看起来像这样。
And it looks something like this.
要设置像素，我要将第1行，第1列和所有平面设置为栗色。
To set the pixel, I’m going to set row 1, column 1, and all planes to the color of maroon.
所以就是这样，我创造了一个像素图像，如果我现在显示，我有我的
So there it is, I’ve created a single pixel image, and if I display that now, I have my
单像素图像，一个坚固的栗色大块。
single pixel image, a big solid block of maroon.
一种非常常见的方式可视化我们混合红色，绿色和蓝色原色的方式是什么
A very common way of visualising the way we mix red, green and blue primaries is what
我们称之为彩色立方体。
we call the color cube.
所以想象我们有一个三维坐标系。
So imagine that we have a three dimensional coordinate system.
三个轴：红色轴，绿色轴和蓝色轴。
Three axes: a red axis, a green axis and a blue axis.
我们将在这里介绍彩色立方体，以及我们在这个角落看到的内容
We’re going to introduce here the color cube, and what we see here in this corner
当我们有最大量的红色但没有蓝色或没有绿色时，我们就像你一样
is when we have the maximum amount of red but no blue or no green, and we see, as you
期待，红色。
would expect, red.
在这里，我们有最大量的蓝色，但没有红色或没有绿色，我们有
Up here, where we have the maximum amount of blue but no red or no green, we have the
颜色蓝色。
color blue.
这个角落我们有最大的绿色，没有红色，没有蓝色。
This corner we have maximum green, no red, no blue.
我们看到颜色为绿色。
We see the color green.
工具箱中有一个文件允许我们显示颜色立方体：函数
There is a file in the toolbox that allows us to display the color cube: the function
被称为rgbcube。
is called rgbcube.
在这里。
And here it is.
现在这是一个三维结构，所以我们想用鼠标进行旋转。
Now this is a three dimensional structure so we want to do a rotation with a mouse.
我要向上移动并选择3D旋转按钮，然后用鼠标抓住它
I’m going to move up here and select the 3d rotate button, and I grab it with my mouse
我可以旋转它。
and I can rotate it.
所以它是一个三维坐标系，这里是原点。
So it is a three dimensional coordinate system, and down here is the origin.
这是红色，绿色和蓝色都为0的地方。
This is where the amounts of red, green and blue are all 0.
所以我们可以在这里看到这个黑暗的角落，那里有0量的红色，绿色和
So we can see this dark corner here, that’s where there is 0 amount of red, green and
蓝色。
blue.
在斜对角的角落，我们可以看到最大量的红色，绿色，
On the diagonally opposite corner we can see where there is a maximum amount of red, green,
和蓝色，那是白色的角落。
and blue, and that’s the white corner.
如果我们看一下这个立方体的不同面，我们可以看到这里的面貌基本上就是这样
If we look at the different faces of this cube, we can see that this face here is basically
看着红色和蓝色的混合物。
looking at mixtures of red and blue.
这张脸在这里看着蓝色和绿色的混合物。
This face here is looking at mixtures of blue and green.
当然，这只是立方体的表面。
Of course, this is just the surface of the cube.
如果我们能够看到立方体内部，我们会发现无数的颜色
If we were able to look inside the cube we would find an infinite number of colors in
那里也是;我们从外面看不到的颜色。
there as well; colors that we can’t see from the outside.